# ANDREA GRIESER

13984 Lanyard Way \* Winter Garden, FL 34787 \* (703)589-6647 \* apgrieser@gmail.com

### SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

A variety of experience highlights the following strengths: excellent customer service skills, enjoy retail environments, secure in software engineering and technical environments; strong teacher, writer, and communicator; self-motivator who takes initiative and enjoys learning new skills

#### WORK HISTORY

## Walt Disney World Resorts, Lake Buena Vista, FL - September 2022 - present

- Quick service restaurant hostess, Star Wars Galaxy's Edge
- Worked all elements of quick service restaurants: plated and served food, bussed and cleaned tables, dining room and outdoor restaurant spaces, performed closing tasks at the end of the night
- Greeted and guided guests to the appropriate locations for food ordering and pick-up
- Prioritized customer happiness and satisfaction, anticipating needs before being asked; considered myself a company ambassador
- Answered all customer questions, verifying they understood the answers, as well as provided food and product recommendations
- Described food and other products so that customers understood the product and were happy with the resulting product
- Handled customer concerns quickly, escalating if necessary
- Took orders, handled cash, credit cards, and special payment cards using electonic registers and iPads
- Prepared some foods and all drinks
- Stocked business areas with necessary equipment and supplies

## Antithesis Operations LLC, McLean, VA - July 2020 - Summer 2022

- Autonomous Software Testing company
- Senior Software Engineer
- Languages: C, C++, Python, Typescript, Nix Expression Language
- Wrote product software as well as performing infrastructure role
- Documentation team lead
- Mentored new employees
- Other technical skills: Linux, Bash, Nix, Sphinx, Terraform, Podman, Google Cloud Platform, AWS services (such as BigQuery, CloudFront, Route53, Lambda, EC2, S3, DynamoDB), FreeBSD (bhyve), mercurial

## Math / Coding Teacher, Loudoun County Public Schools; Ashburn, VA 2009-2020

- Taught Pre-Algebra, Algebra 1, Algebra 2/Trigonometry, Geometry, and Coding at Middle School (teaching Scratch and Python)
- Created complete curricula for all of the courses that I have taught. Other teachers use these
  curricula and the principal has lauded them as a prime reason for our school's strong test
  results
- Responsibilities include lesson planning with technology integration, differentiation (personalized learning), real world learning, teaching, testing, remediation, data tracking, new teacher mentoring, and faculty support
- Led cooperative teacher teams introducing Trello to track schedule and lesson plans
- Created many instructional videos using Keynote and iMovie for the YouTube platform that
  have reach outside of immediate school environment
- Created online classrooms for all courses taught, including self-grading assignments and assessments; especially necessary during closing of schools during COVID pandemic
- · Consistently received highest ratings on evaluations

#### Grieser Software LLC; Ashburn, VA 2001-2009

- Co-founded consulting company that provided original software to Sirius Satellite Radio, Inc.
- Wrote software using distributed .NET architecture using SQL database and web services
- Prime responsibility was user interface
- Provided all technical writing support in the form of manuals, training, and other material
- Provided on-site training and support

### Weight Watchers International; Ashburn, VA 2003-2009

- \* Meeting Receptionist
- \* Greet members, collect payment, weigh members, answer program questions
- \* Sell associated products, closely tailoring to member needs
- \* Provide encouragement, support, and a positive environment

### Storm Control Systems (L-3 Communications) 1991-1998

- · Worked in Herndon, VA and Cambridgeshire, UK offices
- Developed software to support Inmarsat satellite controllers on Unix based operating systems using Gensym's G2 Real-Time Expert System Application, the C programming language, and an SQL database
- Wrote all technical documentation for Storm flagship satellite control product, including user and developer guides as well as training materials for satellite control automation product

### International Business Machines; Gaithersburg, MD 1985-1991

• Created software (design, code, and test) in the JOVIAL and Ada programming languages in support of a government satellite control system

#### Andrea Grieser

- Supported the creation of specification documents and training materials, as well as provided training to operators
- Technical lead of software test (quality assurance) for software configuration management development project
- Project manager for on-site customer in Sunnyvale CA

## Fairchild Republic Company; Farmingdale, NY - 1981-1984

- Internship during summers
- Created FORTRAN programs in support of aerospace engineers

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming language experience: Python, C, C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, Visual Basic, Swift, FORTRAN, JOVIAL
- OS Experience: Windows, macOS, Unix/Linux, NixOS, iOS, iPadOS, IBM 360/370 architecture
- Other technical experience: Terraform, AWS services (such as CloudFront, E2, S3, Lambda), mercurial, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, VSCode, Atom, Trello, git, SQL relational databases, G2 knowledge base (rule based architecture), Xcode (iOS app development in Swift), git, Google G-Suite products, Apple Teacher, Google Certified Educator Level 1

### **EDUCATION**

- Marymount University Master of Education, 2009
- State University of New York at Binghamton BS in Mathematics and Computer Science, 1984